# **Greg Potts**

720 Laurel Ave E., Greenwood, SC 29649 | (864) 200-1162 | pottsga@gmail.com pottsga.com | linkedin.com/in/pottsga

### **Career Profile**

Seasoned IT professional and MBA holder with extensive experience in solving complex business problems. Optimized business processes by implementing Lean and Agile business practices, drastically reducing costs of acquisition of information in terms of labor and resources while enhancing efficiency and validity. Firm believer in the importance of effective change management, especially in the application to IT, since this can contribute to the ability for a firm to gain or hold on to a competitive advantage in their market.

# **Objective**

Now more than ever, competent IT leadership plays such a pivotal role in the success of the organization as a whole.

I am consistently seeking opportunities where I can utilize my skills in business administration alongside my expertise in IT to help businesses improve their value chain through effective application of technology. My objective is to lead in such a way so as to be a good steward of the resources afforded to IT, thereby creating the most value for the institution.

### Core competencies include:

- Software Development Life Cycle
- Information Security
- Lean Business Processes
- Change Management
- Project Management
- Quality Assurance
- IT Operations and Support
- System Administration

#### **Skills**

- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

- DMBS (SQL, PL/SQL, MySQL, No-SQL)
- .NET
- Java

- GNU/Linux
- Cloud Computing
- ERPs
- RESTful APIs

### Education

Liberty University; Lynchburg, VA

• M.B.A. (3.83 GPA)

2019 - 2021

Hiram College; Hiram, OH

• B.A. in Computer Science (cum laude)

2014 - 2017

# **Professional Experience**

Piedmont Technical College; Greenwood, SC

**Director**, IT Applications

2022 - Present

Oversaw a team of individuals that worked in the development and maintenance of custom software solutions as well as the implementation of third-party products in a way that maximizes productivity and uptime. Consistently leveraged a lean mindset in IT business operations so as to provide the optimal solution through the efficient utilization of the applications in place on campus. Doing so worked to

uphold PTC's mission of transforming lives and strengthening communities by providing opportunities for intellectual and economic growth.

#### Ellucian

Senior Consultant 2022

As a senior consultant and senior solutions architect, I sought to understand and meet the business needs of higher education institutions across the country. I worked to meet those needs through the utilization and implementation of Ellucian products, as well as custom software solutions wherein I served as the technical lead.

# Piedmont Technical College; Greenwood, SC

### Systems Programmer / Developer II

2019 - 2022

Served as the lead software engineer for the entire software development lifecycle of over 30 full-stack web applications. Applied knowledge of Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, bash, GNU/Linux, Java, and Systems Administration techniques. Integrated RESTful APIs into ERP systems and utilized these endpoints in enterprise software solutions. Oversaw and interfaced with RedHat Linux servers in order to deploy virtualized software solutions and maximize their availability.

## Systems Programmer / Developer I

2017 - 2019

Responsible for designing, developing, testing, documenting, and implementing custom software solutions based on specifications gathered from meetings with project stakeholders. Administered and oversaw the testing and implementation of new releases of existing Banner ERP system and new applications packages.

### Hiram College; Hiram, OH

# Helpdesk Manager

2014 - 2017

Led a team of 10-15 technicians. Oversaw the day-to-day operations of the Helpdesk, and coordinated with the team to ensure that tickets were being handled appropriately. Maintained the work schedule, assisted with interviewing/hiring new technicians, kept the Helpdesk's website up-to-date with information and documentation (FAQs). Responsible for leading the team in troubleshooting to various level of complexity.

#### Swagelok Co.; Solon, OH

<u>IS Intern</u> 2016

Led multiple company-wide projects that sought to upgrade the fleet of end-of-life manufacturing center workstations while coordinating with management on the manufacturing floor. Developed custom software solutions to locate workstations company-wide. Ensured security of a fleet of Dell workstations by keeping antivirus software up-to-date.

### References

References are available upon request.